<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Palo Alto on Threat Filtering</title>
    <link>https://threatfiltering.com/category/palo-alto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Palo Alto on Threat Filtering</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://threatfiltering.com/category/palo-alto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install SSL certificate on Palo Alto Networks or Cisco ASA Firewalls</title>
      <link>https://threatfiltering.com/install-ssl-certificate-on-palo-alto-networks-or-cisco-asa-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://threatfiltering.com/install-ssl-certificate-on-palo-alto-networks-or-cisco-asa-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;install-ssl-certificate-on-palo-alto-networks-or-cisco-asa-firewalls&#34;&gt;Install SSL certificate on Palo Alto Networks or Cisco ASA Firewalls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firewalls require SSL certificates in one of the following scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Secure management WebGUI access&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Provide SSL-based remote VPN&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Perform peer authentication to establish Site-To-Site VPN tunnels&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Administrator’s tasks include obtaining a certificate either through public or enterprise Certificate Authority, certificate renewal and ensuring that the private key is safe and backed up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article describes basic concepts of a SSL certificate and step-by-step instruction on how to obtain SSL certificate, back it up and restore if the device fail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site-To-Site VPNs on Palo Alto Networks Firewalls</title>
      <link>https://threatfiltering.com/site-to-site-vpns-on-palo-alto-network-firewalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://threatfiltering.com/site-to-site-vpns-on-palo-alto-network-firewalls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;site-to-site-vpns-on-palo-alto-networks-firewalls&#34;&gt;Site-To-Site VPNs on Palo Alto Networks Firewalls&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;IPSec-VPN.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid py-4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Networks firewalls provide site-to-site and remote access VPN functionality. This article covers overview and configuration of IPSec site-to-site tunnels which are compatible with equipment from other vendors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IPSec tunnel is established between two gateways over IP network and is transparent to end devices communicating over this tunnel. Transport network (usually Internet) between gateways is responsible for packet delivery from one gateway to another. Routers on the Internet cannot see original packet content including endpoints’ IP addresses, as packets are encrypted and new IP headers are being added by gateways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Packet Flow And Order Of Operations in Pan OS</title>
      <link>https://threatfiltering.com/packet-flow-and-order-of-operations-in-pan-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://threatfiltering.com/packet-flow-and-order-of-operations-in-pan-os/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;packet-flow-and-order-of-operations-in-pan-os&#34;&gt;Packet Flow and Order of Operations in PAN-OS&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Order of operations in Palo Alto Networks firewalls consists of 6 stages: &lt;strong&gt;Ingress &amp;gt; Session Setup (Slowpath) &amp;gt; Existing Session (Fastpath) &amp;gt; Application Identification &amp;gt; Content Inspection &amp;gt; Egress Forwarding&lt;/strong&gt;. Understanding how traffic is being processed within the firewall is important for writing security and NAT policies and troubleshooting. The following sections provide information about each of the stages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Logical packet flow within Palo Alto firewall is depicted in the diagram below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto Firewalls Configuration Management</title>
      <link>https://threatfiltering.com/palo-alto-firewalls-configuration-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://threatfiltering.com/palo-alto-firewalls-configuration-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;palo-alto-firewalls-configuration-management&#34;&gt;Palo Alto Firewalls Configuration Management&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;ConfigurationManagement-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;candidate-and-running-config&#34;&gt;Candidate and Running Config&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Firewalls are using commit-based configuration system, where the changes are not applied in the real-time as they are done via WebGUI or CLI. To apply the changes, an administrator needs either to enter commit command in CLI or to press Commit button in WebGUI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configuration file is stored in xml format on persistent storage of the firewall. During the boot, it is loaded into memory and becomes running configuration of the device. As different settings of the firewall are applied, such as security policy or system parameter modification – candidate configuration gets changed. It resides in volatile memory and is lost during the system restart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
